CEDRIC P.-E. MANOUAN

Contact: +250 (0) 791 591 607 | Email: cmanouan@alumni.cmu.edu | Linkedin: Cédric pascal-emmanuel MANOUAN | Github: dric2018

SUMMARY

Software/Machine learning engineer with a focus on deep learning for over 3 years.

Experience in deep learning projects for Natural Language Processing and Computer Vision: end-to-end development from data preparation/exploration to model definition and optimization. Ability to evolve and work efficiently in a collaborative environment.

EDUCATION

Master of Science | *Information Technology - Applied Machine Learning* Carnegie Mellon University

August 2021 – May 2023

Master of Science (Semester 7) | *Information Systems and Software engineering* October 2019 – March 2020 Ecole Supérieure Africaine des TIC (ESATIC) Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

Bachelor of Science | *Systems, Computer Networks and Telecommunications* October 2016 – September 2019 Ecole Supérieure Africaine des TIC (ESATIC) - See degree certificate here Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Associate

Summer 2023

Kigali, Rwanda

Carnegie Mellon University

Kigali, Rwanda

• Assisting Prof. David Vernon with the realization of the Situation Model Framework in the CRAM Cognitive Architecture using a Joint Episodic-Procedural-Semantic (JEPS) Associative Memory.

Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant

Fall 2022 - Spring 2023

Carnegie Mellon University

Kigali, Rwanda

- Assisting Prof. Bhiksha Raj in 11785 Introduction to Deep Learning: Natural Language & Audio Processing
 - * Prepared and Co-Lead the Language Modeling homework assignment in Fall 2022
- Assisting Prof. Moise Busogi in Machine Learning for Earth Observation (ML4EO)
- Research in Machine Learning for Earth Observation supervised by Dr. Moise Busogi

Software engineering/Data science Intern

May 2021 – July 2021

Remote

Data science competitions preparation

Developer Intern (BSc. end project)

April 2019 – June 2019

Project of Digital Solutions for the opening up of Rural Areas and E-Agriculture (PSNDEA) Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

- Built an Internet of Things (IoT) system for data acquisition in a cassava field
- Developed a REST CRUD API based on NodeJs and MySQL to store data from both sensors and farmers inputs
- Developed a regression model to predict the yield of a given cassava field based on real-time and stored data
- Deployed the machine leaning model to an edge device (Raspbery Pi 3) using tensorflowJS

SKILLS

Zindi

Languages: French (Native), English (Bilingual, Professional) **Programming**:

- Python
 - * Data visualization
 - * Data manipulation

- * Machine/Deep learning
- * Deep learning
- * API development
- C++
 - * Data structures and Algorithms

PROJECTS AND RESEARCH

Course project - Recommender Systems | CMU-Africa

Fall 2022

Developed a Content-Based Recommender system for scientific papers as part of my mini project for 04800-B Intro to recommender systems at Carnegie Mellon university-Africa

Project link: CBRS for scientific papers

Data science competition - Image classification | ZINDI

Fall 2020

Developed a machine learning model to classify Tuberculosis and Normal X-Ray images

for an educational purpose

Ranking: 7th/104, Click and look for team DataLabCI on the leaderboard

Project link: Tuberculosis X-Rays classification

Data science competition - Audio classification | ZINDI

Fall 2020

Contributed to the development of a machine learning model to classify audio utterances in Luganda and English from Uganda

Ranking: 7th/255, Click and look for team wakanda on the leaderboard

Project link: GIZ-NLP-Agricultural-Keyword-Spotter

Data science hackathon - Image classification | ZINDI

Fall 2020

Contribued to develop a machine learning model to identify whether a person in an image is wearing a face mask

Ranking: 3rd, Click and look for team TheCIA on the leadernoard

Project link: Face mask classification

1st prize Hackathon Level 2 (48h) - Image recognition | ESATIC

May 2018

Contributed to the development of a deep learning model to recognize west African bank notes and coins

1st prize Hackathon Level 1 (24h) - Cryptography | ESATIC

May 2017

Contributed to research and writing in C++ the encryption algorithm behind an executable program

INTERESTS & COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

NLP and Robotics

Spring 2023

Joint Episodic Procedural Semantic Associative Memory

Rwanda, Kigali, CMU-Africa

Rwanda, Kigali, CMU-Africa

Since Spring 2023, I have been contributing to the JEPSAM project.
This project aims to provide an implementation of the Situation Model Framework for the Cognitive Robot Architecture Machine (CRAM) (Beetz et al., 2010).

Data Science ClubLead and coordinator

December 2021 - November 2022

• Participants recruitment for Zindi UMOJAHACK 2022 (enrolled 30+ new users)

Data Science Côte D'Ivoire

2020 - Present

Free tutoring for local students/AI enthusiasts

Côte d'Ivoire, remote

Zindi University ambassador

June 2020 – July 2021

Côte d'Ivoire, remote

- Participating in competitions and hackathons on the platform (username : _MUFASA_)
- Co-lead of the platform development group (improvements and new ideas)
- Participants recruitment for UMOJAHACK 2021 (enrolled 15+ new users)

Co-founder of the Internet of Things and Artificial Intelligence club

2019

ESATIC

Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire